Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajput.
I am the founder of Family First Financial
Services. I have done MBA Finance and have been
working in the corporate sector for 13 years and
today I am presenting to you that
Pramerica Life Insurance Company has
launched an excellent product called Rakshak
Smart, which is for all those people in our country who are
army personnel, paramilitary,
navy, air forces,
who work in high risk areas and
work to protect their country. The
company has launched a guaranteed life insurance policy for them.
If you survive, you get
guaranteed income and even if you die, there is
a huge amount of insurance which you
get immediately. But you get insurance cover
every year. The nominees also
get maturity and tax benefits. There are
many more features in this policy, so
I have explained it in details. If
you are a soldier or in the army or navy, then
definitely watch the video of this policy plan.
If you like the video,
like, share and subscribe to my YouTube channel.
Subscribe Even if you are a common citizen of India,
you can take this policy.
Earlier, it was launched only for the army,
now
this policy has been launched for the common man and ordinary civilians as well,
so they can also buy this policy. It is an
excellent product. Do watch the entire video.
Thank you so much. Talking about the
eligibility criteria of the policy, if you
take the life option policy, then a person from 91
days old to 60 years old
can purchase the policy, but
if you take the Enhanced Life Option, then a
person from 18 years old to 50 years old can
take this policy. The
beauty of this product is that I will
explain it to you in details. The policy
term given in it is 10 years, 12 years, 15 years and 20
years.
You have also been provided with the option of premium payment term of 5 years, 7 years, 10 years and 12
years. Here
you can pay the premium in semi-annually, annually, quarterly or monthly mode as well.  If
you wish to pay in annual mode as well, you
can do so. You are
given many options for premium payment as well.
Here you can purchase
this policy by paying a nominal premium of around Rs. 20,000
and with a healthy premium
you can purchase this policy under good benefits.
Talking about the options of this policy,
two options are given here -
Life Option and Enhanced Life Option. Live
Punch Option is a very common option which is available
in the products of many companies.
If you survive there,
you will get income every year for the last 5 years and
maturity will also come. If death occurs, then the
insurance cover at that time will get the death
benefit and the policy will be closed.
But in Enhanced Life Option, if death
occurs, then premium payment is waived.
Insurance cover is available immediately. Income starts coming every month and
maturity is also available.
I have also explained this in detail in the benefit illustration.
In the policy, you will get Annual
Guaranteed Edition. Annual Guaranteed Edition is available on a
sum of Rs. 000.  For
example, you have purchased your policy for a policy term of 20 years
and
you are getting annual guaranteed addition in the 11th year. If
you look at the table, it says 80, which
means if the insurance cover is ₹000, then
you get an annual guaranteed addition of ₹80.
If the insurance cover is ₹10 lakh, then you will get a
guaranteed addition of ₹80,000. So, for 11th and 12th
year, you get ₹80, for 13th and 14th year, you get ₹
90,000, for 15th and 16th year, you get ₹100, which means ₹1 lakh.
This guaranteed addition also gets added so that
if there is a death, then you get your basic
sum plus the guaranteed addition. The
most important thing is the maturity benefit.
In the maturity benefit, you get
income for 5 years and maturity comes. How does it
come? Suppose your policy term is 10 years, then
you get income from 11th to 15th year.
How much will be the income for the last 5 years? 30%
of basic sum plus 126% accrual
guaranteed addition. I will explain all this in detail
in the benefit section
which will be understandable in simple language.
If the policy term is of 12 years, then
you will get income for 5 years at 13, 14, 15, 16, 17 years,
that too will come at 30 and you will get maturity at 136.
You will get income from 16 to 20 years.
If you had taken a policy term, then it would be 15
years and suppose you have taken a policy term of 20 years, then in the 21st
year, 22nd year, 23rd year,
24th year and 25th year, you will get
% of basic sum. Suppose the basic sum is 10 lakhs,
then you will get an income of 55 lakhs plus
what will be the amount at 13600 at 36. So, on maturity, you will
get 5 lakhs along with 13600 at 25 years.  Let's talk about the death benefit
option in the Enhanced Life Option. That's why
I'm explaining it in a little detail
because this policy has been specially designed
for the armed forces, for the Indian
army brothers, for the Navy, for the
Air Force. The risk there is much
higher and if something happens to the earning member there, then
they can benefit a lot from this insurance.
If this policy has been taken, then suppose
if this option has been taken and let's say
you have purchased an insurance cover of Rs. 10 lakh, the
basic sum assured on which
all the calculations are done, then
what are the options in the death benefit here? The first
benefit is written as Immediate Benefit, that is, the
nominee will get Rs. 10 lakh immediately. The
second is Waiver of Premium, that is, the premium will be
waived. Third, in Immediate Benefit,
you will see that you get this Annual Guarantee Addition
along with Rs. 2
per month, that is, Rs. 10 lakh has been paid at Rs.
200.  240000 per month per year
and the policy term is for as many years,
suppose the policy term was 20 years and
income was to come in the last 5 years and it will be in the first
year only, then for the remaining 19 years, the income
that was to come will come at 240000 every year, that is,
you will get 00 per month and
what will you get in the benefit,
how much will you get on maturity, as I
told you, you should see here, suppose the policy
term is 20 years, then 250 per basic sum
means 2 lakh,
I have explained all this calculation in simple language in the benefit illustration, let us
understand the
benefit illustration of Enhanced Life Option for Armed Forces,
I will try to explain both Life Option and Enhanced Life Option,
let us see
now let us see the
benefit illustration of Enhanced Life Option of this plan,
how it works, it will
also come attached in your policy bundle, let us assume there is
a person whose name is Indian Armed
Forces, I have mentioned the name of the person in the proposal itself  I have named it
Indian Armed Forces so that it is understood
that I am making it for the Armed Forces
where their age is 35 years. Your name
can be Ajay Sir, Vijay Sir, whoever you
are in the Army, it will be
written here. Suppose your age is 35 years, you are male, you are a
non-smoker and you are
purchasing the Primary Life Rakshak Smart Policy and the option you are selecting in it is
Enhanced Life
option. Now you have to
pay the premium here for 12 years. The policy will
run for 20 years. If you look at the category of the plan,
non-linked means this is a uly policy, which
means it is not based on the share market and is
non-participating, nor is it a bonus
policy, that is, this is a 100% guaranteed
plan which will be written in your policy band as
guaranteed that
you are purchasing a guaranteed policy
[Sangeet]
Now let's see because your
risk profile is a little higher in the Army,
due to this you are paying
occupational flat extra loading here.
I will also tell you what this loading or premium is.  Let me explain in detail, let's assume
you are taking an insurance cover of 10 lakhs in the policy,
all the calculations are done on the basic sum assured,
saving booster, you get a death
benefit of
860000, how you get this 860000 on death,
I am explaining this in details also,
now you will see here, if a normal
person takes a policy, if an Indian civilian
takes a normal policy, then his premium comes to
13730 plus GST at 45 in the first year, then
GST at 24, now if you are in the Indian Army or
Navy or Air Force due to risk profile,
your premium is coming to 144000,
instead of 133 you have to
pay GST on it, but you will get this policy, you will get a
claim of 100, the fee will be guaranteed,
not even a single paisa will be less or more,
now how does this option work, first let me
tell you that if nothing happens to you,
you survive, then
what benefits will you get while you are alive, suppose you are
paying premium for 12 years, you paid premium for 12 years
After filling it, you have to wait
and in the 21st year, 22nd year, 23rd year,
24th year and 25th year, how much income will you get,
₹ 5 lakh, in the 21st year,
see maturity benefit is written on it, on
which guarantee is written, then in the
22nd year also ₹ lakh, in the 23rd year also 55 lakh, in the
24th year also ₹ lakh, in the 25th year also 5 lakh
plus the maturity amount that comes at 136, then
13600 becomes 10 lakh, at 136 it becomes
13600, so you get this 18600 at 25,
where did it come from at 136, let me tell you, from
which calculation did it come through the browser, which I have already
told you in the beginning, here
you will get this that whatever comes in the last year of your policy between 21st and 25th year,
at 136
comes the guaranteed addition, then you get 00  If that
happens then the overall amount is 18600. If you finally get a match then if you
survive then you will definitely get this
money. Now because your
profile is risky, anything can happen,
you are protecting the country, so
what will your family and your nominee get? Let us
understand with an example, suppose you had paid the first
premium and unfortunately you died. If you
unfortunately died then the
insurance cover of Rs 10 lakh,
look here it will be written as immediate, the immediate death benefit will be written,
that Rs 10 lakh will be given
to the nominee immediately, all the remaining
premiums that were to be paid will be waived,
your nominee will not have to pay any of them, after that
you will get Rs 2 of Rs 10 lakh i.e. per month
i.e. 240000 per year and remaining 24
years are still left, so you will get this money per month, so in
total you will get Rs 460000 i.e.
your nominee
plus you will get Rs 20000 per month after 25 years.  You will get 10 lakhs and
250% of 10 lakhs, I will also tell you where did that come from, this
calculation
you will see here, guaranteed maturity
multiple, if you are taking a policy term of 20 years, then
you get it at 250, so now
you will see here, this becomes 25 lakhs,
so 10 lakhs plus 45600 becomes 5560000
plus 25 lakhs, your total will be
860000, if death occurs in the first year,
similarly death occurs in the second year, in the fifth year, in the 10th
year, the
amount of death benefit will be available in writing in front of you,
if you survive then you are
guaranteed to get this money, you will
also get the benefit of income tax, you will
also get a loan, whatever money comes will be tax
free and if the share market goes somewhere, if the
rate of FD goes somewhere, you will definitely get the
money which has been given in writing,
if you ever have to surrender in between,
then you can also get the surrender amount  You
can see here that the
word 'guaranteed' has been used to show how much
money you can surrender and get back. Now let's
see option number two which is the life option. If
you are purchasing the policy through the life option, then
what will happen in the life option, everything
is the same, your premium will be reduced a bit here,
you will see here the premium has
become 125000 instead of 144, but what will happen because of this is that the
money that you were going to get per month will
not come, in case of death, you will
not get the ₹ lakh that you were getting at the end,
normally you will get the death benefit,
you will see here that the immediate death
benefit will be given and the policy will be closed,
if death does not happen, then the 55
lakhs that you were getting, 18600 that you were getting will definitely come, so if you survive, then
this will be cheaper for you,
but if death happens, then
this option will be very good for you
because in this you
get 2 per sum of money and all other things are also available,
if you want to pay more premium,
here  I am taking you an example of one lakh rupees or
more than that, you
can pay one lakh rupees, you can pay 5 lakh rupees, you can
pay 50000 rupees as per your need, you can pay the
premium as per your need, now if you have purchased the policy and have
taken the live option, in case of death,
what does the nominee get, first he gets the
sum added on the plus the annual guaranteed
addition which I had explained to you
earlier, now what is the definition of sum as death, first you are
paying 11 times the annual premium of one lakh rupees,
so you have got an insurance of 11 lakhs, second the basic
sum which is 10 lakhs as I am explaining in simple language, on
which all the calculations are done,
third 105% of the premium you have paid
and fourth let us
understand the definition of x percentage x%, for example, the
customer's life is 15 years old, he was
paying a premium of one lakh rupees, so of ₹ one lakh, you will get the
higher one out of these four plus
your annual  There are guaranteed additions, you will get them. If there is
no death in the like option, then the normal income that you get every year,
you will get that income for the last
5 years. Now I am explaining to you the benefit
illustration for the common man, for the
civilians, if they purchase this policy, then
what benefits will they get in the live option
and
what benefits will they get in the life enhanced life option. Let us
understand the benefit illustration for the common man.
Now, if this
policy was earlier made by the company only for the army,
now it has been launched for the normal person as
well for Indian civilians, so a
normal person can also purchase this policy.
For example, that is why I have taken the
option of common army here, that
if a common man purchases this policy,
his age is 35 years, everything is kept the same,
but his premium will be
13730 here, along with GST, it has been
mentioned here. All other benefits will be
shown in the same way that 10 lakh 45 lakh everything
remains  Same, there will not be much change
and if they select the second life option, then
their premium is coming to 000
and the benefit etc. You can see
what they will get in case of death, if there is
no death then it is the same amount, so because there is a
little more risk in the army,
that is why you are paying this loading here, a
little bit and for civilians there is
no loading here because the
risk is comparatively less, if you
look at the under rating extra here then you will
not see anything, in this way you
can buy this policy, it is an excellent policy which is
made for the armed forces and this type
of product, that too a guaranteed product,
probably no other company in the industry has the age
of now, so if you
want to buy this policy from me then contact me
on 9094 3412, my name is Anil Rajput, you can
FFFS my YouTube, there are already
more than 300 insurance related
videos there which will help you in taking your financial decisions,
thank you, let's
talk so much about the policy  Regarding other benefits,
surrender benefit, in this policy, if
you have paid minimum two premiums, then your
surrender value will be generated, which will be
written in the table itself that how much
surrender amount you will get. Talking about tax
benefit,
you get tax benefit up to ₹ lakh under section 8C of Income Tax,
plus the income that comes on maturity is
tax free under section 1010D of Income Tax. If your premium is
5 lakh or less per annum or more than 5 lakh, then the
taxation rules have come in the new budget,
but you can invest up to ₹ lakh
and the
maturity coming from it remains tax free.
Talking about loan in the policy, because these are
saving traditional policies, it is a guaranteed
policy, then you will also
get the facility of reduced paid up of RPU in it.
Suppose you had taken a policy term for a long time,
10 years, 12 years, you had to
pay the premium, but due to some reason you could not pay,
you were able to pay only two or three premiums, then which
You paid the premium in the proposal,
your benefits will start in that proposal and will get reduced. Let us
talk about revival in that proposal, suppose if due to
some reason you are
not able to pay the premium for one or two years, then the
company will give you a revival period of one year, by paying the
premium for the remaining years for which you have not paid, you
can revive the policy, you can start it or continue it. If we
talk about the
grace period in the policy, then
you will also get a grace period of 30 days in this,
suppose you have purchased the policy on 1 February 2024,
your
renewal is coming next year, due to some reason you are not
able to pay, then you will get a time of one month, you
pay the premium in the policy once a month, the
benefits will continue, so finally if
I describe this product, then this
is an excellent product, 24 insurance companies are
working in India at present, but till now no
company has a guaranteed age of now like this for the Indian Army, Navy and Air Force,
this is one of the  This
is a unique product where you will get 100% guaranteed
income and tax benefit. In case of death,
you get a huge amount which is
immediately given to the family members, plus it
also comes every month so that household expenses can be easily met.
Maturity is also given. So
many unique features are given in this policy.
If you like this product
and want to purchase from me, then you
can contact me. My name
is Anil Rajput, mobile number 990 940 3412. If you
like the video, then
subscribe to me from Kanpur and share this video with your
army members or all the army brothers.
If they want to purchase the policy, then
thank you so much.